Hey, welcome here today Mike.
Mike さん、本日は面接に
I'm really glad to have you in here for the interview.
お越しいただきありがとうございます
What I'd really like to get started with is
まずはマッピングとローカライゼーションについて
just a question around mapping and localization. Are you ready?
質問させていただきますがよろしいですか
Sure.
はい
Okay, great. So, my first question for you is to just describe
それでは始めますではまず、衛星によるオブジェクトの位置特定の
the process behind how satellites determine the position of an object.
背景にあるプロセスについて説明してください
Sure. So, satellites typically float around in geosynchronous orbit,
はい衛星は通常、対地同期軌道で周回しています
and when they're in that orbit,
衛星はその軌道にある場合
the Earth is actually spinning and they're actually broadcasting the signal back down.
回転している地球に信号を送ります
Then, depending on where you are on Earth,
地球のどの場所にいるかによりますが
you have some sort of a GPS packing,
何らかの GPS 機能があれば
your GPS picks up the signals from the satellites and then translate
GPS が衛星からの信号を受信し、それを緯度・経度を使って
that to a coordinate or location system using latitude and longitude.
座標または位置測定システムに変換します
Great. Is that usually something
なるほどこの位置特定に必要な衛星は
that just takes one satellite or do you need multiple satellites to determine this?
通常 1 台ですか、それとも複数ですか
So, you can do it with one satellite.
1 台の衛星でも可能ですが
The problem with one satellite is the area is usually really large,
1 台だと対象エリアが広すぎるという問題が起きます
so you typically want anywhere between three to five satellites
そのため、より正確な位置を特定するには
on average to actually get a much more accurate position.
平均 3～5 台の衛星が通常必要となります
Interesting. Do you think that's something you can use for like
興味深いですねこれはロボット工学アプリケーションにも利用できると思いますか
a robotics application or is that more for autonomous vehicles as well,
それとも、どちらかというと自律型自動車向けでしょうか
or is that not accurate enough?
あるいは測位精度が十分ではないでしょうか
I think you can use it to some extent depending on how accurate you need to be.
必要とする精度の度合いにもよりますが、ある程度は利用できると思います
In terms of something like a self-driving car maybe,
自動運転車などに関しては
it's just probably not the best.
最適とは言い難いですね
I think you're only accurate within
精度が保証される範囲は数フィート以内
a couple of feet so typically around plus or minus seven feet or so.
通常はプラスマイナス 7 フィート程度です
In that case, you could actually be predicted to be in the different lane.
これだと、別の車線にいると予測される可能性があります
So, that's actually very dangerous in something like a self-driving car.
ですので、自動運転車などに利用するのはかなり危険ですが
But if I'm flying a UAV or something like that out in the middle of a field,
無人航空機などの上空の飛行体なら
that might be good enough for the purpose that I'm in.
目的に十分に適うかもしれませんね
Great. Can you think of any approaches that
なるほど。ロボット工学アプローチで精度が
might be more accurate in a robotics approach?
より高くなる可能性があるアプローチとして、何が思い浮かびますか
So, I think what you could do is you can actually take some of
この GPS 信号情報を使って
this GPS signal information and you can
異なるタイプのアルゴリズム
actually couple it with some different types of algorithm,
たとえばパーティクルフィルターとか共通フィルターのような
some sort of localization algorithm something
何らかのローカライゼーションアルゴリズムと
like a particle filter or maybe a common filter.
組み合わせることができると思います
Have you ever implemented something like a particle filter or common filter?
パーティクルフィルターや共通フィルターのようなものを実装したことはありますか
Yeah. So, I've done both actually.
ええ、どちらもありますよ
What did you have to do in order to implement those or
実装のために何を行う必要がありましたか
what about them makes them better than just GPS?
GPS よりも精度を高めるために何に取り組みましたか
Yeah. So, one of the things that you do is there's typically two phases.
はい。通常 2 つの段階を行う必要があります
So, there's usually a measurement phase and then there's an update phase.
測定段階と更新段階です
So, with the measurement phase, you're actually gathering the information that
測定段階では衛星から収集した
you've collected from the satellite
情報を集め
and making a prediction as to where you're going to move.
移動先についての予測を行います
Then in your update phase,
次に更新段階で
you're looking at where your new location is in the measurement information.
新しいロケーションが測定情報のどこに位置するかを確認します
Again, adjusting for an error and then kind of going back and fine tuning,
ここでもやはり、誤差調整や微調整の作業を繰り返すので
so you're basically making a closed feedback loop.
基本的には閉フィードバックループが形成されます
Great. Okay. I think that covers most of what I had for this question.
わかりました。この質問についてはこれで以上です
So, let's go ahead and move on to the next topic.
では次のトピックに移りましょう
Great. Thanks.
わかりました
All right.
ありがとうございました